Exfar Nanda Micola Android Developer

exfarnanda45@gmail.com

West Jakarta, Jakarta



A programmer with 2 years of experience, who also worked on small-medium scale projects and 1 year of experience becoming a freelance trainer made me experience, work hard, highly motivated, teamwork, communication skills, analytical skills, and a fast learner. Interested in mobile development, especially native Android.



exfarnanda



exfarnanda1945



+6288221525710



https://s.id/exfarnanda45

Work Experience

1. Freelance Trainer Mobile Programming

ID-Networkers • West Jakarta, Jakarta

06/2022 - Present

- Substitute instructor at Mobile Programming Training (Java, Kotlin, Flutter) also helps and delivers the participants to understand concepts and code.
- Instructor at Bootcamp IDN Android Kotlin (February-March 2023) with 40 participants from across Indonesia.
- Design and develop a free project Android app using Kotlin with implement Http request (Retrofit and OkHttp), Local Database (Room DB), Dependency Injection (Dagger Hilt), MVVM, Coroutines, Flow, Paging, Data Store, View Binding + Data Binding and Navigation also translate the wireframe into XML code.
- Integrate the android app with Firebase Service (Realtime Database) and Google Map API.

2. Full Stack Web Developer

Berkah Lestari Group · Semarang, Central Java

02/2020 - 04/2022

- Prepare staging and production server with EC2 AWS Service. Set up, secure, and manage the
 database (PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQL Server), Web Server (NGINX), WordPress, and some
 necessary tools so that the application runs as it should.
- Configure and manage pipelines CI/CD with Gitlab CI and create bash script for auto deployment to the server.
- Design and implement a database with a database scheme using TypeOrm and develop tools to simplify dynamic queries.
- Build REST APIs using TypeScript (HapiJs and GraphQL) by applying strong design patterns, architecture, OOP, and Dependency Injection.
- Design and build a responsive Front-End App with ReactJs library, split into small components and applying efficient clean code also integrate the app with REST APIs.
- Worked with monorepo for several projects and familiar with development tools like Trello.

3. Front End Web Developer

KodingWorks • Semarang, Central Java

09/2019 - 12/2019

- Build and develop Progress Web App with a dashboard using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Translate design and wireframe into code using ReactJs and Material UI Component Library with responsive layout.
- Integrate the app with REST APIs using Axios Http Client, and Firebase Service (Firestore, Storage, and Authentication) and build a cross-platform app for Android using Ionic Capacitor.
- Familiar with development tools like Trello and Clockify.

Android Development Skills

- Make HTTP Requests using Retrofit third-party library with methods GET and POST and added parameters, query, headers, custom headers, and set timeout connection using Okhttp.
- Design and create a local database using Room Database covering the scope like creating the entity database, creating DAO with the use of custom raw query and function for creating dynamic queries, creating type converter function for inserting complex data to the database, and implement offline caching.
- Creating a paging source to handle data pagination.
- Applying MVVM architecture also manage service and instance with Dagger Hilt dependency injection.
- Applying repository patterns for accessing local and remote data sources, creating business logic before
 data in and out from the repository, also implementing coroutine flow to create data stream process and
 error handling.
- Create a view model with receive and process data from the repository and convert the flow data into the live data object.
- Design and build UI using XML code with various layouts, and components from Material Design, responsive for all mobile devices, and applying light and dark themes to the app.
- Implement View Binding and Data Binding for easy access to components, Jetpack Navigation for navigation between activity/fragments, and Data Store for saving non-complex data with use for the session, theme, and app configuration.

Education

1. IDN Academy Scholarship

Mobile Programming • West Jakarta, Jakarta 06/2022 – Present

2. Santren Koding Scholarship

Web Programming • Semarang, Central Java 07/2019 – 09/2019

3. SMK N 1 Gombong

Computer and Network Engineering • Kebumen, Central Java 05/2016 – 06/2019

Dicoding Certification



